export const FINANCIALACCOUNTINGA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A quality of accounting information is that it should be?",
A: "Profitable",
B: "Verifiable",
C: "Appreciable",
D: "Depreciable",
answer: "B. Verifiable",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. When the letter “C” is written in front of an entry in the folio column of a cash book, it shows a?",
A: "Double entry",
B: "Cash entry",
C: "Contra entry",
D: "Journal entry",
answer: "C. Contra entry",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. To show the evidence of payment to a government ministry, the revenue collector issues a?",
A: "Receipt voucher",
B: "Payment voucher",
C: "Treasury receipt",
D: "Treasury card",
answer: "A. Receipt voucher",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The primary concern of shareholders in a business is the?",
A: "Ascertainment of taxable profit",
B: "Dividend payable",
C: "Ability to pay interest",
D: "Welfare of employees",
answer: "B. Dividend payable",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. In a not for profit organization, accumulated fund is?",
A: "Current assets plus fixed asset less total liabilities",
B: "Long term liabilities plus current liabilities",
C: "Fixed assets plus current assets plus long term liabilities",
D: "Fixed assets less long term liabilities less current liabilities",
answer: "A. Current assets plus fixed asset less total liabilities",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Purchases for 2017 was?",
A: "N3,480,000",
B: "N2,850,000",
C: "N2,700,000",
D: "N2,550,000",
answer: "D. N2,550,000",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The cost of goods sold was",
A: "N3,330,000",
B: "N2,910,000",
C: "N2,760,000",
D: "N2,610,000",
answer: "D. N2,610,000",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. In public sector accounting, the salaries of employees is classified as?",
A: "Capital expenditure",
B: "Capital receipts",
C: "Recurrent expenditure",
D: "Recurrent receipt",
answer: "C. Recurrent expenditure",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Kadiri paid his debt to Suleman by cheque. The accounting entries in Kadiri’s books are debit?",
A: "Bank account; credit Suleman’s account",
B: "Bank account; credit debtors account",
C: "Suleman’s account; credit bank account",
D: "Suleman’s account; credit cash account",
answer: "C. Suleman’s account; credit bank account",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The concept which seeks to prevent profits from being overstated is?",
A: "Materiality",
B: "Consistency",
C: "Prudence",
D: "Periodicity",
answer: "C. Prudence",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Total cash receipts for the period is?",
A: "N99,000",
B: "N64,000",
C: "N50,000",
D: "N35,000",
answer: "A. N99,000",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The cash balance at the end of the period is?",
A: "N99,000",
B: "N64,000",
C: "N35,000",
D: "N34,000",
answer: "C. N35,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The directors of Olu Ltd recommended a dividend of 10% on 1,000,000 ordinary share capital of GHc2.00 each. The amount of dividend declared is?",
A: "GHc200,000",
B: "GHc100,000",
C: "GHc20,000",
D: "GHc10,000",
answer: "A. GHc200,000",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Goodwill is recognized in partnership when?",
A: "The business makes a huge profit",
B: "The business has adequate bank balance",
C: "The business is dormant",
D: "A new partner is admitted",
answer: "B. The business has adequate bank balance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The mark-up on a product is 2/3, the margin is?",
A: "3/5",
B: "2/5",
C: "1/3",
D: "2/9",
answer: "B. 2/5",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Quick ratio is calculated as x-y:z Where?",
A: "X = stock, Y= current asset and Z= long term liabilities",
B: "X=current assets; Y= debtors and Z= current liabilities",
C: "X = current assets; Y= stock and Z= current liabilities",
D: "X=current assets; Y= stock and Z= current assets",
answer: "C. X = current assets; Y= stock and Z= current liabilities",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The closing capital is?",
A: "D16,800",
B: "14,300",
C: "8,300",
D: "D7,300",
answer: "B. 14,300",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The working capital is?",
A: "D6,440",
B: "D3,880",
C: "D3,500",
D: "D1,320",
answer: "D. D1,320",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. In a single entry accounting, purchases are ascertained using a?",
A: "Trading account",
B: "Debtors control account",
C: "Statement of affairs",
D: "Creditors control account",
answer: "D. Creditors control account",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Goods brought from Samah for Le1,600 was entered into Shamail’s This is an error of?",
A: "Compensation",
B: "Commission",
C: "Original entry",
D: "Principle",
answer: "B. Commission",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. When the closing stock is undervalued, the cost of goods sold will be?",
A: "Overstated and the gross profit understated",
B: "Understated and the gross profit overstated",
C: "Overstated and the gross profit overstated",
D: "Understated and the gross profit understated",
answer: "A. Overstated and the gross profit understated",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Where a fixed capital account is manufactured, partners share of profit is transferred to the?",
A: "Debit side of capital account",
B: "Credit side of capital account",
C: "Credit side of partner’s current account",
D: "Debit side of partner’s current account",
answer: "C. Credit side of partner’s current account",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. When bank charges are deducted from a customer’s account, the balance on the bank statement would be?",
A: "More than the cash book balance",
B: "Less than the cash book balance",
C: "Equal to the cash book balance",
D: "Added to the cash book balance",
answer: "B. Less than the cash book balance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Companies issue shares to the public in order to?",
A: "Reduce the number of directors",
B: "Reduce the number of shareholders",
C: "Raise capital",
D: "Generate profit",
answer: "C. Raise capital",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Salah took two textile materials worth GHc500 from his business for his children’s use. This would be treated as a?",
A: "Loan",
B: "Stock",
C: "Drawings",
D: "Sales",
answer: "C. Drawings",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Ogah’s share of profit was?",
A: "GHc51,150",
B: "GHc50,250",
C: "GHc34,000",
D: "GHc33,500",
answer: "A. GHc51,150",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Ajem’s current account balance was?",
A: "GHc65,000",
B: "GHc60,000",
C: "GHc32,400",
D: "GHc40,000",
answer: "C. GHc32,400",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Interest on drawings amounted to?",
A: "GHc6,000",
B: "GHc1,500",
C: "GHc900",
D: "GHc600",
answer: "B. GHc1,500",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Debtors control account is kept in the?",
A: "Sales ledger",
B: "Nominal ledger",
C: "Personal ledger",
D: "General ledger",
answer: "A. Sales ledger",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Where there is provision for depreciation, fixed asset is shown in the balance sheet at? \nI. Cost less total depreciation for the period only \nII. Cost less total depreciation to date \nIII. Written down values",
A: "I only",
B: "II only",
C: "I and II only",
D: "I and III only",
answer: "C. I and II only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The partners whose liability goes beyond his capital is a?",
A: "Nominal partner",
B: "General partner",
C: "Limited partner",
D: "Dormant partner",
answer: "B. General partner",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. An effect of increase in the provision for depreciation is?",
A: "Decrease in gross profit",
B: "Increase in net profit",
C: "Increase in gross profit",
D: "Decrease in net profit",
answer: "D. Decrease in net profit",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Uncredited cheques refer to the cheques not yet credited?",
A: "In the cash book",
B: "By the bank",
C: "By the drawer",
D: "In the ledger",
answer: "B. By the bank",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Interim dividend paid in a year is?",
A: "Debited to the income surplus account/ profit and loss appropriation account",
B: "Credited to the income surplus account/profit and loss appropriation account",
C: "Debited to the profit and loss account",
D: "Credited to the profit and loss account",
answer: "A. Debited to the income surplus account/ profit and loss appropriation account",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. A feature of government accounting is that the?",
A: "Fixed assets are depreciated",
B: "Objective is to report profit made by the government",
C: "Accounts are prepared on accrual basis",
D: "Accounts are prepared on cash basis",
answer: "D. Accounts are prepared on cash basis",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The prime cost is?",
A: "$57,000",
B: "$45,000",
C: "$42,000",
D: "$39,000",
answer: "C. $42,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Factory overhead cost is?",
A: "$25,000",
B: "$15,000",
C: "$12,000",
D: "$7,000",
answer: "C. $12,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Capital and drawings account are kept in the?",
A: "General ledger",
B: "Purchases ledger",
C: "Sales ledger",
D: "Private ledger",
answer: "D. Private ledger",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Set off is carried out in the control account when?",
A: "A business organization is both a customer and a supplier",
B: "Customers refuse to pay their debts",
C: "The debtors settle their accounts",
D: "Customers cheque is dishonoured",
answer: "A. A business organization is both a customer and a supplier",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The credit sales is?",
A: "Le11,730",
B: "Le9,149",
C: "Le2,581",
D: "Le2,518",
answer: "B. Le9,149",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. An example of a nominal account is?",
A: "Kofi and Ali account",
B: "Plant and machinery account",
C: "Profit and loss account",
D: "Cash and bank account",
answer: "C. Profit and loss account",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The concept that recognizes revenue at the time of sale and not only when cash is received is?",
A: "Cost concept",
B: "Realization concept",
C: "Accrual concept",
D: "Duality concept",
answer: "B. Realization concept",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The accounting concept which stipulates that income and expenses should be matched to determine profit or loss is?",
A: "Cost concept",
B: "Accrual concept",
C: "Objectivity concept",
D: "Realization concept",
answer: "B. Accrual concept",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The document used to correct an undercharge in an invoice is?",
A: "Credit note",
B: "Debit note",
C: "Receipt",
D: "Voucher",
answer: "B. Debit note",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Carriage inward for Dept B is?",
A: "D1,500",
B: "D960",
C: "D800",
D: "D640",
answer: "B. D960",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Net profit for Dept A is?",
A: "D6,340",
B: "D5,860",
C: "D4,960",
D: "D4,900",
answer: "B. D5,860",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Net profit for Dept B is?",
A: "D17,460",
B: "D16,660",
C: "D16,260",
D: "D15,940",
answer: "D. D15,940",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The depreciation per annum is?",
A: "Le2,360",
B: "Le2,280",
C: "Le2,200",
D: "Le1,600",
answer: "C. Le2,200",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The net book value of the machine as at 31st December 2017 was?",
A: "Le44,000",
B: "Le41,200",
C: "Le39,000",
D: "Le38,760",
answer: "C. Le39,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Subscription owing $6,000(31/12/14): Subscription in advance $4,000 (31/12/14) Cash received as subscription during the year was $80,000 The subscription for the year was?",
A: "$90,000",
B: "$82,000",
C: "$78,000",
D: "$70,000",
answer: "C. $78,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]